{"tossups": [{"question": "In 1623, an alchemist started manufacturing objects in this country for military use that are still used as instruments today. Avedis Zildjian [zil-jin] worked in this country, the setting of an opera in which Belmont rescues Konstanze from Pasha Selim. Western orchestras imported the triangle, bass drum, and cymbals from this country, the setting of Mozart\u2019s<em> Abduction from the Seraglio</em>. For the point, a craze for what country\u2019s music was inspired by the Janissary military bands?", "answer": "<b> Turkey</b> (accept the<b> Ottoman</b> Empire)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Dance"}, {"question": "For the point, name this home country of Conor McGregor, who was born in Dublin.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Ireland</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Description acceptable. The planning of this event included a fake polio vaccination program in Bilal Town in an attempt to recover DNA samples. \u201cGeronimo\u201d was controversially used as the code name for this event\u2019s target, whose body was taken to the USS<em> Carl Vinson</em> and buried at sea. This initiative was carried out without the knowledge of President Zardari\u2019s government by Seal Team Six. For the point, name this 2011 military action in Abbottabad, Pakistan, that killed the leader of Al Qaeda.", "answer": "<b> kill</b>ing of<b> Osama bin Laden</b> (accept either or both names; accept equivalents that mention the<b> death</b>, <b>assassination</b>, etc. of<b> Osama bin Laden</b>; accept Operation<b> Neptune Spear</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Flouting of this law in Passamaquoddy Bay prompted fears of rebellion. This legislation reacted to the execution of Jenkin Ratford, who worked for James Barron. This law, prompted by the Chesapeake-Leopard Affair, was replaced by the Non-Intercourse Act, which was in turn replaced with Macon\u2019s Bill No. 2. A political cartoon attacking this legislation depicts the \u201ccursed Ograbme,\u201d a snapping turtle, nicking a man. For the point, name this law that banned all exports in Jeffersonian America.", "answer": "<b> Embargo Act</b> of 1807", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This leader\u2019s admiral, Marcus Agrippa won the Battle of Naulochus to put down a revolt in Sicily. This man publicized the Donations of Alexandria, in which his rival gave Roman land to another power. This man removed Lepidus, a fellow member of the Second Triumvirate, from power after defeating the son of Pompey the Great, and this man later won the battle of Actium against Mark Antony. For the point, name this adopted son of Julius Caesar who changed his name upon becoming the first Roman Emperor.", "answer": "<b> Augustus</b> Caesar (or<b> Octavian</b>; accept Gaius<b> Octavius</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Participants in this event were enraged by the hanging of Mangal Pandey at Barrackpore. Lucknow and Cawnpore were besieged at the onset of this event. Bahadur Shah II was accused of aiding this event and exiled to Rangoon, marking the end of the Mughal dynasty. This rebellion led to the establishment of direct British rule and was prompted by the use of bullet grease derived from pork and beef fat. For the point, name this 1857 Indian mutiny of Muslim and Hindu soldiers.", "answer": "<b> Sepoy</b> Mutiny (or equivalents, like revolt or rebellion)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A saint of this name from Nursia is considered the main patron saint of Europe and wrote a book of precepts for monastery life. The fifteenth Pope of this name attempted to mediate peace talks in World War I. The most recent Pope of this name was indoctrinated into the Hitler Youth as a child in Germany. For the point, give this papal name, taken for the sixteenth time by Joseph Ratzinger, whose retirement preceded the leadership of Pope Francis.", "answer": "<b> Benedict</b> (accept Saint<b> Benedict</b> of Nursia, Pope<b> Benedict</b> XV and/or XVI)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man described the death of John F. Kennedy as \u201cchickens coming home to roost\u201d and advocated for the usage of arms to obtain equality in the \u201cBallot or the Bullet\u201d speech. Shortly after converting to Sunni Islam and breaking with Elijah Muhammad, this man was assassinated by three agents of the Nation of Islam. For the point, name this Muslim minister of the 1950s and 60s.", "answer": "<b> Malcolm X</b> (accept Malcolm<b> Little</b>; accept el-Hajj Malik el-<b>Shabazz</b>; do not accept\u201cMalcolm the Tenth\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Robert Lowie, a graduate of this school, wrote<em> The German People</em> as part of a study funded by the Office of War Information during World War II. The American Museum of Natural History was used extensively by a member of this school to analyze the<em> Mind of Primitive Man</em>. Alfred Kroeber\u2019s <em>Anthropology</em> was published after his tutelage under Franz Boas at this university, where Ruth Benedict taught for many years. For the point, name this Ivy League university that offered the first anthropology degree in the United States from its campus in New York City.", "answer": "<b> Columbia</b> University Page 2", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Anthropology"}, {"question": "This founder of the Hunters of the Alps helped stall an Austrian attack on Trentino at the Battle of Bezzecca. This man met his wife Anita while serving the Republic of Rio Grande del Sol in the Ragamuffin War. After forcing Francis II\u2019s retreat to Gaeta, this man won the battle of the Volturnus in his \u201cExpedition of the Thousand.\u201d This man conquered the Kingdom of the Two Sicilies for Victor Emmanuel II during the Risorgimento. For the point, name this leader of the Redshirts and hero of Italian unification.", "answer": "Giuseppe<b> Garibaldi</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This city is home to the Barmaley Fountain, which depicts six children dancing around a crocodile. Vasily Zaytsev killed over 200 people while defending this city from an attack that the invaders described as \u201crat war\u201d due to the close-quarters urban warfare. The Mamayev Kurgan hill overlooks this city, which Friedrich Paulus\u2019 Sixth Army was unable to capture after over five months of fighting. For the point, name this city where, in 1943, the Red Army decisively defeated the Germans on the Volga River.", "answer": "<b> Stalingrad</b> (accept<b> Volgograd</b> before \u201cVolga River\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One side in this event was forced to ask Quebec governor Lord Dorchester for help after suffering defeat at Petersham. An attempted shutdown of courts at Great Barrington and Concord preceded this event, in which Benjamin Lincoln managed to keep the Springfield Armory in federal hands. This event helped spur the end of the Articles of Confederation and the creation of a stronger federal government. For the point, name this 1786 to 1787 uprising of Massachusetts farmers.", "answer": "<b> Shays\u2019 Rebellion</b> (do not accept Shay Rebellion; the leader was Daniel Shays)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This state\u2019s Native American reservations include Crow Creek and Yankton, as well as Pine Ridge, where the AIM occupied a town in 1973. A landmark in this state was originally planned for the Needles and instead created at a site revered as \u201cSix Grandfathers\u201d by the Lakota Sioux. The Wounded Knee Massacre took place in this state, whose Black Hills are the location of a Gutzon Borglum sculpture featuring four portraits. For the point, name this home state of Mount Rushmore.", "answer": "<b> South Dakota</b> Page 3", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This partner of Robert Wagner and Averell Harriman orchestrated the downfall of Tammany boss Carmine DeSapio in revenge for her son\u2019s defeat in an election for State Attorney General. She promoted the Encampment for Citizenship program on her estate at Hyde Park. This first American delegate to the United Nations authored the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and chaired the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women. For the point, name this \u201cFirst Lady of the World,\u201d the wife of Franklin Delano.", "answer": "<b> E</b>leanor<b> Roosevelt</b> (prompt on Roosevelt)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A man in this play compares a dangerous ruler to a serpent\u2019s egg that cannot be allowed to hatch. Another character in this play describes his former friend, noting \u201cThe evil that men do lives after them; / The good is oft interred with their bones.\u201d This play includes a funeral oration that begins \u201cFriends, Romans, countrymen,\u201d as well as the non-historical line \u201cEt tu, Brute?\u201d An assassination on the Ides of March is the subject of, for the point, what history play by William Shakespeare?", "answer": "The Tragedy of<b> Julius Caesar</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Drama"}, {}, {"question": "A park in this city contains the Rest House, as well as a building designed by Jan Letzel now known as the Genbaku Dome. This city\u2019s Peace Memorial Park also includes a monument based on the story of Sadako Sasaki, who was a victim of \u201cblack rain\u201d here. On August 6, 1945, Paul Tibbets piloted the <em>Enola Gay</em> and dropped \u201cLittle Boy\u201d over this city. For the point, name this Japanese city, the target of an atomic bombing three days before Nagasaki?", "answer": "<b> Hiroshima</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One former Prime Minister of this country founded the company Mediaset and was known for his extravagant \u201cbunga bunga\u201d parties. For the point, name this country currently led by Matteo Renzi and recently led by Silvio Berlusconi.", "answer": "<b> Italy</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "A mutiny against this man at Puerto San Julian was recorded by his assistant Antonio Pigafetta. Charles V funded the voyage of this man, whose expedition lost every ship except for the<em> Victoria</em>. This explorer was killed in the Battle of Mactan by Lapu Lapu in the modern day Philippines, but not before naming a strait between Tierra del Fuego and the South American mainland. For the point, name this Portuguese explorer who led the first expedition to circumnavigate the globe.", "answer": "Ferdinand<b> Magellan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Spiro Agnew presented one of these animals as a gift to Norodom Sihanouk of Cambodia. One of these creatures was kept as a pet by Leo X and named Hanno. One of these animals named Abul Abbas was presented to Charlemagne by Harun al Rashid. Rama IX owned ten of these animals, the last of which died in 2006. These creatures adorn the naval ensign of Thailand, where they are a symbol of royal power. For the point, name these animals who are targeted by ivory poachers.", "answer": "<b> elephant</b>s", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A storm following this battle allowed one side to launch the Cosmao sorties and reclaim the<em> Neptune</em>. Pierre Villeneuve\u2019s<em> Bucentaure</em> was captured in this battle after Cuthbert Collingwood\u2019s<em> Royal Sovereign</em> joined up with the<em> Victory</em> to split a French and Spanish column. Horatio Nelson was killed by sniper fire in the heat of this battle. For the point, name this 1805 naval battle of the Napoleonic Wars, now commemorated by a namesake square in London.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Trafalgar</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This president announced, a week after 22 amateur boxers were killed in a plane crash in Poland, that the U.S. would boycott the upcoming Summer Olympics. This president negotiated with Omar Torrijos to return the canal zone to Panama and mediated peace talks between Egypt\u2019s Anwar Sadat and Israel\u2019s Menachem Begin at Camp David. For the point, name this president whose handling of the Iranian Hostage Crisis probably cost him the 1980 election against Ronald Reagan.", "answer": "James Earl \u201cJimmy\u201d<b> Carter</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The aftermath of this event affirmed Congress\u2019 right to compel testimony via the case<em> McGrain</em> <em>v Daugherty</em>. Thomas Walsh was able to expose this scandal after discovering a $100,000 loan from Edward Doheny. After receiving bribes in exchange for the rights to Elk Hills, Secretary of the Interior Albert Fall became the first Cabinet member to be imprisoned in this scandal. Navy oil fields were leased to private companies in, for the point, what political scandal that rocked Warren G. Harding\u2019s administration?", "answer": "<b> Teapot Dome</b> scandal Page 6", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}